Finding Aid for Gregory Stempfle papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Gregory Stempfle papers 1982-2014
Stempfle, Gregory
1 linear foot
2015008 Aa 2
Gregory Stempfle is an active member of both the Libertarian Party of Michigan (LPM), as well as the Libertarian Party of Wayne County local affiliate. The collection contains various newsletters, convention packets, leadership directories, a scrapbook, and other materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Gregory Stempfle (donor no. 11165 ) in September, 2014.
The collection is open to research.
Gregory Stempfle has worked actively with multiple affiliates of the Libertarian party since the 1990s. He primarily worked closely with the Libertarian Party of Wayne County and the Libertarian Party of Michigan, even serving two terms as their newsletter editor.
The Gregory Stempfle papers are comprised of printed materials collected from his involvement with the Libertarian Party of Michigan (LPM), as well as its local affiliates. The collection is arranged alphabetically.
A large portion of the collection consists of LPM convention packets, highlighting the convention events, as well as the legislation discussed. Packets are included from the years Stempfle attended, ranging from 1997-2014. A packet is contained for the 1988 Nominating Convention, which was held in a suburb of Detroit. This packet includes programs for the event, as well as documents regarding the planning of the convention.
One folder contains materials from the Wayne County local affiliate office and includes newsletters, meeting notes, and correspondence from the 1990s. The collection also includes a scrapbook that holds color photographs from events, correspondence, and flyers from the Livingston County local affiliate.
Stempfle collected campaign materials from a number of Libertarian candidates running for office. Pamphlets, biographies, and campaign materials are included for candidates running for state positions. Some of these politicians include Jon Coon, Diane Barnes, John Stempfle, and more. Pamphlets are also included for candidates running for local office such as Christopher Gonzalez, Martin Howrylak, Mark Carney, and more. The collection contains campaign information for candidates running for national office, including information from the LPM regarding their support of said candidate.
Subjects:
corpname; Browne, Harry, 1933-2006.; Libertarian Party of Michigan.; Libertarianism--Michigan.; Libertarians--Michigan.; Livingston County (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Means, Russell, 1939-2012.; Michigan--Politics and government.; Paul, Ron, 1935-; Wayne County (Mich.)--Politics and government.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbook.
- Gregory Stempfle papers
  - Detroit Nominating Convention Material, 1981-1988 (Box 1)
  - Harry Browne Libertarian for President, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Libertarian Party of Michigan 25th Anniversary, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Libertarian Party of Michigan Annual Report, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Libertarian Party of Michigan Convention Materials
    - 1999-2000, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
    - 2005-2010 (Box 1)
    - 2011-2012, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Libertarian Party of Michigan Leadership Directories, 1982-2002 (Box 1)
  - Libertarian Party Newsletters (different counties), 1992-2008 (Box 1)
  - Livingston County Libertarian Party scrapbook, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Local Candidates for Office, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Libertarian Newspapers, 1986-1987, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets (Box 1)
  - National Impeach Clinton A.C.T.I.O.N. Committee (Box 1)
  - Ron Paul for Libertarian President Campaign, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Russell Means for President, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Wood County Libertarian Party, 1993-2009 (Box 1)
Related material
The Bentley Historical Library holds collections of papers belonging to other people involved with the Libertarian Party in Michigan and a number of Libertarian newsletters
Dick M. Jacobs papers, 1980-1993 Finding aid available online
Dale Haviland papers, 1964-1991, bulk 1970-1979 Finding aid available online
Metro-Detroit Libertarians newsletters
The Michigan Libertarian: newsletter of the Libertarian Party of Michigan
Libertarian Party of Wayne County newsletters
Libertarian Party of Oakland County newsletters